[music]
from our Rams block party here at
Hollywood Park. Good afternoon and
welcome to our final postdraft show
presented by Zillow, JB Demarco and the
head coach of your Los Angeles Rams,
Sean McVey, draft number 10. Wow. How
about that?
>> Where does the time go?
>> I know. I feel uh feel great though.
Don't feel like it's draft number 10.
feel excited and, you know, to be able
to come away with five picks. You know,
I I think when you look at it, we've got
a really good roster situation where you
want to make sure that you're drafting
five guys that you envision being able
to make the team and are they going to
be able to be active on our 48 and
everybody's going to earn everything
they get. But I think we're in a really
good position and we were able to
identify a lot of the things that we
wanted to address and and it kind of
came to fruition like we had hoped. Do
you take a a big deep breath after the
draft like everyone else or do you like
this is the beginning of the year for
me?
>> It's it's the beginning, but I mean it's
it'll be good to be able to you know I
think number one what you appreciate is
the amount of work that's gone into this
from less his scouts for really the
totality of the year. The coaches have
put in a lot of work over the last
couple months. But when you do end up
coming away with five picks to Marco,
you feel really good. And I'm excited
for these guys to get here. You know,
that's the problem. We got to wait for
them to be able to kind of whatever the
semantics are and and once they get into
the building, then we'll be ready to put
our arms around them and embrace them
and get them to go, you know, get them
as part of this team.
>> Our first chance to hear about your day
three pick. So, why don't we start there
and work our way back in time. You come
away with a receiver and a defensive
lineman today.
>> Yeah, and that's big. You know, I think,
you know, CJ Daniels was a guy that we
really liked and he can play inside, he
can play outside. Started his career at
Liberty, had a you know, good year at
LSU and then finished up at Miami. But
man, he's he's a fun guy to watch. He's
got a great story. Um, and we're excited
about him. And I think when you really
look at it with Puka and Devonte being
our clear-cut top guys, and then we've
got some guys that played a lot of
meaningful football with Xavier Smith,
Mumfield, obviously Jordan Whittington,
and he'll fit into that mix. And we've
got some guys that were on the practice
squad last year that'll get a chance to
be able to compete. So, that was big.
There was a collective buyin and then to
be able to get big Tim U, that's big.
You know, he DeMarco, he's Demarco's
kind of guy. Uh he can go hash to hash.
That's how I know you're an athletic
nose. There you go. Uh you know, he's
he's got great play energy. Uh great
block destruction and you can really see
good twitch for a guy of his size. And
he'll come in and we've got some depth.
He's a little bit different than some of
the guys that we do have, which offers a
little bit different flavor, but I know
GIF is excited to be able to coach him
and and we'll look forward to embracing
both those guys with open arms.
>> Well, I was looking on the draft. I was
like, uh where's the defense? You know,
you're going to draft a defensive guy
somewhere in here, right?
>> Yeah. He signed three defensive guys in
free agency. I knew he was going to do
that. But here's the thing, you know, I
think when you really look at it, you
know, this is a lot of cool stuff going
on. Um, you add four new players in free
agency with Cardona as the long snapper.
You get Grant Stewart who's going to be
a special teams demon, but he also can
provide some uh depth at the inside
linebacker spot and then the two corners
is big. So, we got some, you know, big
time cheers in the background, too.
>> Big time. It's for you, though. See?
Yeah.
>> I don't think [laughter] so.
>> Uh, the crown jewel of this class has to
be Trent McDuffy. I mean, it probably
didn't get celebrated enough this
weekend, but he's very much a part of
this weekend.
>> It's a huge part of it. I mean, when you
look at it, especially just based on
some of the needs that we had looking at
the landscape of the draft, I mean, what
a stud he is to come away with who we
deem as the most complete corner, you
know, or one of the most complete
corners in the league. And then, you
know, you get to know him and he's an
even more impressive person. Uh, to be
able to add he and Jaylen Watson is big.
Really excited about watching Forbes
continue to develop under Jimmy Lakes,
you know, leadership. Um, and I think
Josh Wallace is a guy that's played a
lot of meaningful football that just
kind of consistently delivers and got
some other young guys, but this is going
to be exciting and we'll add some
undrafted free agents that always come
out. Uh, guys earn everything that they
get. Doesn't matter where they're
drafted. You know, we have open eyes
about finding the best players for our
football team. And that's what's
exciting about this time of year.
>> One more thing about Watson and and
McDuffy. What impresses you about
corners you're playing against? Like
what gets into your mind when you're out
there with those
>> play style? I think movement, you know,
ability to be able to compete, be
competitive at the point of contact, you
know, I think some of those different
things, you know, how do you play with
your back to the football? You know, are
you comfortable in some of those look
and lean situations when you get a
chance to be able to attack at the
football? Are you catching it? Um, and
then if you have to come up and tackle,
you know, what does that really look
like? Both these guys are violent crack
replaceers. Both these guys have been
activated as blitzers. Both these guys
can cover to the boundary or to the
field. Trent's played the star position
as well. Uh, so there's not really any
limitations, but they're different
flavors, but that's the beauty of it and
and uh we're really excited about both
those players.
>> All right, let's talk pick 13. And
before we talk about the player, I'm
curious about the approach just in a
vacuum. I'm sure there were a basket of
players there
>> who could have helped impact winning
with Matthew Stafford, right? Supported
him and instead the Rams
organizationally go in a direction where
Matthew Stafford is going to help grow
up, pick 13, and he can impact winning
down the road. I'm curious how you got
to the point where you felt convinced
that was the right choice for the Rams.
>> I think the biggest thing JB when you
look at it is is number one, Matthews
earned the right to be able to say
whenever his time comes and we've been
on a year-to-year basis with him. I'm
hopeful that that's as long as he wants
to be able to go. But the reality is is
that hey, he's going to do his thing
this year and if he says after 18 years
or if he says I'm ready for 19, I'm
nobody's more excited about that. But
what we do have to have is a contingency
plan in place for whenever he decides.
And I think that's the key thing. You
know, this will be on his terms. Um, but
that position is so important. You know,
you don't you when you look at it and
you're saying, "Okay, let's evaluate the
body of work. Do you think this guy has
a chance to be a starting caliber
quarterback?" And the evaluation was fun
because you're evaluating 15 games of a
lot of different inventory, a lot of
different things that you would like to
be able to see, uh, that I think really
do translate to our level of play and
what he was asked to do. I think it's a
great situation for him to come in and
learn behind one of the all-time greats,
but hey, that'll be on Matthew's terms.
Um, you know, there was a lot of back
and forth dialogue that we did have and
I think our job is to be able to think
for the long and the short and then also
part of the approach that we take with
Matthew is, hey, how do we keep him
mentally, emotionally, and physically as
fresh as possible with the way we
approach OTAAS, with the way we approach
training camp? That's where Jimmy was
such a vital part of our team last year
that I think Matthew acknowledged and
really, you know, both Tai and and Stson
will be that uh when we figure out those
opportunities to be able to keep Matthew
as fresh as possible leading into that
Australia opener.
>> Two things. So, was it the position like
you had a need, we got to fill that spot
behind Matthew or was it the kid you
fell in love with? Well, I think it's a
combination of both because you're not
going to reach, you know, you you
obviously had a void right there that
you're looking at with with, you know,
respect to the confidence I have in
Stson and how far he's come,
>> but that position is so important. Um,
and really for the training camp, the
OTAA's approach that we talked about,
but also, you know, whenever Matthew
decides, you want to be able to have
contingency place, you know, plans in
place, uh, because he's earned the right
to be able to do that. and if he said
that uh you know hey I can guarantee
that I'm going to play three to four
more years it's probably a different
approach but because we have gone
yeartoyear and because we deem the body
of work uh worthy of consideration in
that spot that was kind of what led into
the decision
>> is that a touchy thing I was telling
Maurice the other day it's the one
position player the running back the
quarterback you can only play one I'm
used to competing with guys that a tough
deal when you have an established dude
but hey look we're going to go in this
direction does that get to people
sometimes
>> well I think what you do is You
communicate with clear, open, and honest
communication. You give intense in terms
of what is what is behind the thought
process. And you get the reigning MVP in
the league, you know, and he is
incredibly secure and he's competitive
as hell. And sometimes that brings out
the best in guys. But, you know, the
thing I think I've made clear throughout
the weekend is is with respect and
excitement about Tai, this is Matthew's
team. You know, he's not coming in to
compete with Matthew. Matthew's our guy.
He's earned that right. But I think, you
know, what makes Matthew a first ballot
hall of famer is is whatever it is, you
know, I I talk, you look at Michael
Jordan, The Last Dance, you know,
whatever it is that these great do to be
able to continue to allow them to
perform at those upper echelon levels on
a consistent basis. You know, that's
what makes them special. But Matthew is
so motivated and inspired to want to do
right for his teammates because of the
kind of competitor he is. and I'm
looking forward to being able to get
back to work with him cuz uh he looks
pretty good even just watching him throw
and catch with guys you know that we
can't be a part of right now.
>> Great institutional support in terms of
your coaching firepower for someone like
Tai to come in and work with not just
yourself, not just Matthew, but what a
time to have Cliff Kingsbury on staff
given his background and what he might
be able to offer that young man in
addition to Dave and Nate.
>> Yeah, and that's and that's big. You
know, I I don't think you can have
enough guys with a quarterback
background. Obviously Dave and Nate will
work really closely with him. Cliff's
got just such a great big picture
perspective. And even being able to add
a guy like Brian Johnson who's working
with the defensive coaches, but he's got
an incredible background as a
quarterback. I mean, and all four of
those guys played quarterback at a
really high level for us.
>> Cliff's bigger than I thought, by the
way.
>> He's a stud.
>> I shook his hand. He stood up. I'm like,
"Good. You're you're big. That's a big
dude."
>> We had, you know, I mean, he and Dave
are both quarterback draft picks and we
gave uh homage to we got five guys on
the staff that were drafted. Uh, you
know, it was cool.
>> Good place to learn. Absolutely. Can you
name the five?
>> Dave.
>> Yeah. Well, I just gave you two. I mean,
jeez.
>> Uh, on the staff that were drafted as
quarterback. Oh,
>> you should get the other two. It's
pretty.
>> You got them. Who?
>> Guys drafted as quarterbacks.
>> No, no, no, no, no. Okay. I Guys that
were NFL draft picks that are on our
coaching staff.
>> On the coaching staff.
>> So, those are the two that were
quarterbacks. Yeah. Robert Woods.
>> Robert Woods. Brian Allen.
>> There you go. There's four. Who's the
fifth?
>> He was a 12th round pick in 19
>> Yarbs. Y [laughter]
there. That's right. Idaho.
>> That's right. That's exactly right.
Idaho's finest. No doubt about it.
>> I'm just making sure that I can name all
five of your tight ends. Sean, my
goodness, you got a whole portfolio of
them.
>> You can. We got Pentagon personnel
coming to your [laughter] theater near
you. All five tight ends in there.
>> But I knowing you want to probably have
four of them active on game day to make
sure you're plus one so that you can
have that luxury throughout the season.
I imagine
>> I think it's important. You know, I
think the other thing that you really
look at is is we really didn't start
leaning into this until about midway
through the season. And you want to be
careful of not wearing guys down, you
know, and so do you have guys that can
complement each other? Obviously, KBY,
you know, Higs, Ferg, Davis Allen,
unbelievable contributions that those
guys made, but you got to get somebody
else in there that has the chance to be
able to supplement those guys for the
snaps that are accumulated over the
course of a season. Um, Max is a good
compliment to that group, but you got to
I mean, that's a really good group of
those top four guys are really special.
Scooter Huff and and Smash Ball do a
great job with that group, and we're
excited to be able to add Max into the
mix and see what he can do cuz I think
it's important for us to figure out what
is this next iteration of our offense.
Obviously, 13 personnel is going to be a
part of it. What that really looks like
is what we're still kind of working
through as uh as we're navigating the
offseason. I was thinking that when you
when you when you you you pulled Max
Claire, like how far can you take this
13 personnel? Like how far can you take
this multiple tight end sets and really
set the world on fire? I know why I
can't stand tight ends because as a
defensive player, I can never get
settled. There's always somebody moving.
You change my my my run
responsibilities. Is that what you're
looking for out of those personnel
groups and and how to attack?
>> No, man. Your run responsibility set.
The second and third levels are the ones
that got to clean it up like that. But
I'm just kidding. Uh yeah, I think what
we want to be able to do is continue to
figure that out. I think a lot of the
stuff, you know, we were kind of working
through in the middle of the season, you
know, you're not naive to the fact that
people are going to study it and figure
out, all right, how to be able to stop
you. So, how can we try to be able to
grab the pen back and figure out ways to
put our players in the best spots? And
that's what's exciting about it. But
really, all of our players give us give
us a chance to be able to do that. If
you had asked me this time last year if
that's what we would be, I would never
have envisioned it. It kind of
organically came across. So, I think you
have to have an open mind. you have to
be ready to adjust, adapt, and then
ultimately act and and put these guys in
the right spots.
>> You said this in all sorts of ways, but
you don't pick up this season right back
at the NSU championship game level. Um,
and when you get there on Monday,
there's going to be a group of men in
the facility who want to earn helmets
and be a part of this 2026 team. I know
a lot of this weekend is about building
for the future. Can you maybe finish by
giving us a sense of where you're
launching 2026 and how you feel going
into it with this group? Well, I think
the important thing right now is is
we're establishing foundations and
setting fundamentals this time of year
just based on how the offseason is set.
I think every single year it's the most
important thing is how do we come
together as a team? How do we really in
our own way start to establish the
culture, the vibe? What does this group
look like? But what does it look like
for us to come together in the greatest
team sport that there is? How do we
establish a culture, a play style that's
in alignment with the things that we
deem important? And and we're in the
midst in the very early stages of that.
You know, we started our offseason
program last week on Monday. It's great
to be able to just have a little bit
more noise in the building and see these
guys' faces. They're just focusing on
lifting and meeting with their coaches
individually on kind of their individual
plans for improvement and then not
losing sight of the things that they do
at a high level. But, um, I'm really I I
feel really fortunate and blessed going
into year 10. I love the coaching staff
that we're surrounded with and and I
love the collective group that's coming
back. I love the four new players that
we did add and I'm excited about the
five guys and you guys know there's
always going to be some undrafted free
agents that make a name for themselves
as well. So, uh it'll be great to be
able to have some new new faces, build
some new relationships and see where we
can take this thing in 2026.
>> Geek, man. I am I'm starting to, you
know, look like you a little bit better
than we're getting there. Yeah, we're
getting there. [laughter]
>> My offseason program hasn't started yet.
Uh thanks for joining us for a postdraft
show presented by Zillow. Demarco and I
are going to go enjoy the block party
here at Hollywood Park. Sean, you've
earned uh
>> some hours off this weekend.
>> Always good to see you guys.
>> Catch you next week.